{"sections":{"main":{"type":"main-product","blocks":{"title":{"type":"title","settings":{"display_on_card":false,"text_align":"text-left"}},"price":{"type":"price","settings":{"display_on_card":false,"show_on_sale_sticker":false,"text_align":"text-left"}},"quantity_selector":{"type":"quantity_selector","settings":{"display_on_card":false,"show_label":true}},"variant_picker":{"type":"variant_picker","settings":{"display_on_card":false,"option_style":"drop_down","hide_option_labels":false,"enable_color_swatches":false}},"baf3083e-d14d-435d-bca3-100d6ac490ce":{"type":"buy_buttons","settings":{"display_on_card":false,"show_price":true,"enable_payment_button":true,"show_pickup_availability":false}},"a17e90c4-acc9-4f1d-af84-828ae4cb2289":{"type":"description","settings":{"display_on_card":false,"truncate_description":false,"text_align":"text-left"}}},"block_order":["title","price","quantity_selector","variant_picker","baf3083e-d14d-435d-bca3-100d6ac490ce","a17e90c4-acc9-4f1d-af84-828ae4cb2289"],"settings":{"crop":"","image_shape":"default","desktop_media_width":"lg:col-span-7_lg:col-span-5","show_slideshow_arrows_on_desktop":false,"enable_image_zoom":false,"enable_video_looping":true,"autoplay_videos_on_desktop":true,"media_mobile_width":"w-full","thumbnails_position":"left","thumbnail_crop":"aspect-w-1 aspect-h-1","thumbnail_shape":"heptagon","hide_media_shadow":false,"thumbnail_size":"large","show_thumbnails_on_mobile":false,"color_scheme":"tertiary","use_gradient_background":false}},"502b5396-367c-41d7-b6c7-a1f7892bb3c8":{"type":"testimonials","disabled":true,"blocks":{"template--16010042015906__502b5396-367c-41d7-b6c7-a1f7892bb3c8-16684121765ed8f7a4-0":{"type":"testimonial","settings":{"rating":"5_stars","quote":"<p>A quote from a customer or staff member can help show of your products' unique selling points.<\/p>","source":"Source"}},"template--16010042015906__502b5396-367c-41d7-b6c7-a1f7892bb3c8-16684121765ed8f7a4-1":{"type":"testimonial","settings":{"rating":"5_stars","quote":"<p>A quote from a customer or staff member can help show of your products' unique selling points.<\/p>","source":"Source"}},"template--16010042015906__502b5396-367c-41d7-b6c7-a1f7892bb3c8-16684121765ed8f7a4-2":{"type":"testimonial","settings":{"rating":"5_stars","quote":"<p>A quote from a customer or staff member can help show of your products' unique selling points.<\/p>","source":"Source"}}},"block_order":["template--16010042015906__502b5396-367c-41d7-b6c7-a1f7892bb3c8-16684121765ed8f7a4-0","template--16010042015906__502b5396-367c-41d7-b6c7-a1f7892bb3c8-16684121765ed8f7a4-1","template--16010042015906__502b5396-367c-41d7-b6c7-a1f7892bb3c8-16684121765ed8f7a4-2"],"settings":{"display_on_card":true,"title":"Customer Reviews","max_width":100,"disable_media_style":false,"crop":"","image_shape":"default","desktop_slide_width":20,"autoscroll_mode":"1","color_scheme":"primary","use_gradient_background":false}},"product-recommendations":{"type":"product-recommendations","settings":{"show_product_recommendations":true,"display_on_card":false,"enable_quick_buy":false,"product_recommendations_heading":"You may also like","max_products":"3","product_tiles_aspect_ratio":"","image_shape":"","color_scheme":"primary","use_gradient_background":false}},"4a1ae5e2-2a30-49d5-bff6-769272b96cd1":{"type":"faq","blocks":{"template--16010042015906__4a1ae5e2-2a30-49d5-bff6-769272b96cd1-1668414519e48829f5-0":{"type":"question","settings":{"question":"WHAT IS AN ENERGY GEL?","answer":"<p>Energy Gels provide portable and easy-to-digest calories from carbohydrates that deliver immediate and sustained energy without the stomach distress.<\/p><p>GU Energy Gels use a combination of simple and complex carbohydrates. Carbs become the main source of energy as our bodies transition from sedentary to an active state and exercise intensity increases.<\/p>"}},"template--16010042015906__4a1ae5e2-2a30-49d5-bff6-769272b96cd1-1668414519e48829f5-1":{"type":"question","settings":{"question":"WHY DO I NEED ENERGY GELS?","answer":"<p>The body does have a limited carbohydrate supply, but not enough to sustain higher intensity activity for long periods of time. Thus, as you deplete your carb supply, performance suffers. You need energy in the form of carbohydrates to keep going in longer, more intense efforts.<\/p>"}},"template--16010042015906__4a1ae5e2-2a30-49d5-bff6-769272b96cd1-1668414519e48829f5-2":{"type":"question","settings":{"question":"HOW IS ROCTANE ENERGY GEL DIFFERENT?","answer":"<p>A ROCTANE Energy Gel contains 3x the branched chain amino acids (BCAA's) and 2x the electrolytes compared to our original Energy Gels. They also contain the amino acids taurine (to help maintain heart contractility and improve cardiac output during long exercise sessions) and beta-alanine (to help promote formation of the intramuscular buffer carnosine). ROCTANE Energy Gels deliver the same combination of carbohydrates and same number of calories. ROCTANE Energy Gels are a key tool for high-intensity or prolonged activity when nutrient depletion and muscle damage occurs rapidly.<\/p>"}},"template--16010042015906__4a1ae5e2-2a30-49d5-bff6-769272b96cd1-1668414519e48829f5-3":{"type":"question","settings":{"question":"WHY ARE ENERGY GELS MADE WITH TWO TYPES OF CARBOHYDRATES?","answer":"<p>Carbohydrates are efficient energy, and we use a blend of carbs to deliver more energy into the bloodstream as efficiently as possible. Our system of dual-source carbohydrates provides an “express lane” for each carb to deliver energy to your body much quicker than a single source of carbs, which helps you avoid “the bonk” during training and racing.<\/p>"}},"template--16010042015906__4a1ae5e2-2a30-49d5-bff6-769272b96cd1-1668414519e48829f5-4":{"type":"question","settings":{"question":"WHEN SHOULD I TAKE AN ENERGY GEL?","answer":"<p>We pack 100 calories into our Energy Gels because, in general, the body can digest roughly 120-240 calories per hour during exercise. If you tried to eat more, the body would divert blood from your muscles back to the gut to handle the excess food\/calories. If your metabolism is slower, then one Energy Gel every 45 minutes works just fine. If you have a faster metabolism, try ingesting one Energy Gel every 30 minutes and see if it agrees with your digestion system. We always recommend practicing your nutrition plan to determine what works best for you.<\/p>"}},"template--16010042015906__4a1ae5e2-2a30-49d5-bff6-769272b96cd1-1668414519e48829f5-5":{"type":"question","settings":{"question":"HOW DO I EAT AN ENERGY GEL? DO I HAVE TO EAT THE ENTIRE ENERGY GEL AT ONE TIME?","answer":"<p>Rip open the top and squeeze the entire packet into your mouth—don’t save half of it for later. It’s also completely appropriate to “sip” the Energy Gel over the course of a couple minutes rather than slamming the it all at once. Our Energy Gels were designed to be taken in one shot to provide you with maximum benefits.<\/p>"}},"template--16010042015906__4a1ae5e2-2a30-49d5-bff6-769272b96cd1-1668414519e48829f5-6":{"type":"question","settings":{"question":"CAN I USE AN ENERGY GEL FOR A STRENGTH WORKOUT OR YOGA? ","answer":"<p>Sure! While GU Energy Gels were designed for endurance sports, they can be used anytime you need energy to fuel a workout, regardless of what type. Exercise is either aerobic or anaerobic, but you’re burning calories either way.<\/p>"}},"template--16010042015906__4a1ae5e2-2a30-49d5-bff6-769272b96cd1-1668414519e48829f5-7":{"type":"question","settings":{"question":"HOW DOES THE CAFFEINE IN GU ENERGY GELS HELP ME? ","answer":"<p>GU Energy Gels and ROCTANE Energy Gels come in both caffeinated and non-caffeinated flavors. Caffeine is more than just a morning pick-me-up. Strategically adding caffeine to your nutrition plan before and during exercise can help keep your mind sharp, decrease perceived effort, boost your endurance, and delay fatigue<\/p>"}},"27f762fc-c580-4269-b289-da9d334708a4":{"type":"question","settings":{"question":"DO GU ENERGY GELS FREEZE?","answer":"<p>Yes, but well below zero. They will thicken in cold weather, so keep your Energy Gels close to your body to keep it warm.<\/p>"}},"48a3ab3a-938b-447c-bbdd-54e70c1be370":{"type":"question","settings":{"question":"HOW LONG DOES AN ENERGY GEL TAKE TO WORK?","answer":"<p>Right away! The fructose converts quickly into an energy molecule that your muscles can tap within minutes. The maltodextrin, which makes up 70-80% of the carbohydrate blend (depending on flavor), takes several minutes longer. Because of this delay, your muscles enjoy a steady stream of energy instead of one gigantic sugar rush and a corresponding crash.<\/p>"}},"2ac8f77b-14da-4c16-87af-6c69d87d2dda":{"type":"question","settings":{"question":"ARE ENERGY GELS SAFE FOR CHILDREN? ","answer":"<p>Yes, if they’re playing sports, on a hike, or active, GU Energy Gels can help kids just as much as they help you. You may want to keep them away from flavors that contain caffeine, though.<\/p>"}},"21860d85-a529-4c2f-a455-7ecb43a377ae":{"type":"question","settings":{"question":"ARE GU ENERGY GELS KOSHER, VEGAN-FRIENDLY AND GLUTEN-FREE?","answer":"<p>GU Energy Gels and ROCTANE Energy Gels are both kosher certified, gluten-free and vegan-friendly.<\/p>"}},"2674c916-cbf6-44f1-a520-ac1073e338cf":{"type":"question","settings":{"question":"WHEN SHOULD I EAT ROCTANE ENERGY GELS?","answer":"<p>ROCTANE Energy Gels were designed to help provide nutritional support for prolonged and\/or more intense exercise. Therefore, you will find ROCTANE Energy Gels especially beneficial during exercise which requires extra recovery time and\/or where you need help with preventing fatigue, increasing concentration, focus, and decreasing perceived effort.<\/p><p>When you are going big or the workout is going to require more of you because of the weather, terrain, environment, intensity, etc.– use ROCTANE Energy Gels. During a more typical workout – use original GU Energy Gels.<\/p>"}},"1c9d6314-4a5a-43bd-ba09-45e4fd5ae6da":{"type":"question","settings":{"question":"HOW CAN I USE ROCTANE ENERGY GELS WITH ROCTANE ENERGY DRINK MIX? ","answer":"<p>If you already use ROCTANE Energy Gels, you can substitute two-and-a-half ROCTANE Energy Gels for one serving of ROCTANE Energy Drink Mix. Remember, the body can typically handle around 120-240 calories per hour, so keep this in mind when combining the two. This will help tailor energy intake to your needs and provide the beneficial ingredients found in both the gel and drink. While many ingredients are similar in the two products (carbohydrates, BCAAs, and caffeine) each has unique ingredients which may also help improve performance. Therefore, using both products will help provide every nutritional advantage possible to athletes who demand the best from themselves and their nutrition.<\/p>"}},"1dc840b5-6dc2-416d-935a-e1c0e3c755b2":{"type":"question","settings":{"question":"WHY DOES ROCTANE ENERGY GEL HAVE THE SAME NUMBER OF CALORIES AS ORIGINAL GU ENERGY GEL? ","answer":"<p>You find 100 calories of carbohydrates in both ROCTANE Energy Gel and GU Energy Gel because there’s no reason to add more. The gut can only absorb so many calories at a time during exercise, especially when most of your blood is being delivered to your hard-working muscles. If you add too many calories during intense exercise, your body can’t send enough blood to your gut to digest the carbs, making your gut cramp, forcing you to slow down.<\/p>"}},"f8c42ae2-3634-437d-818d-d4dd77c748fd":{"type":"question","settings":{"question":"DOES ONE ROCTANE ENERGY GEL EQUAL TWO GU ENERGY GELS? ","answer":"<p>No. ROCTANE Energy Gel is designed to help provide added nutritional support for prolonged exercise, which is why there are additional amino acids and sodium. However, they have the same number of calories (100) per gel as our original Energy Gel.<\/p>"}},"7cf91238-7b3b-42e5-8e35-1bdb783c4d0f":{"type":"question","settings":{"question":"HOW WILL THE ADDED ELECTROLYTES AND AMINO ACIDS IN ROCTANE ENERGY GEL BENEFIT ME? ","answer":"<p>ROCTANE contains more sodium than the original GU Energy Gel and sodium is the main electrolyte lost in sweat. Supplementation with sodium can help prevent cramping as well as minimize the chances of hyponatremia.<\/p><p>The additional amino acids in ROCTANE Energy Gel serve several important functions, including acting as a fuel source for working muscle, and helping promote muscle recovery following exercise. ROCTANE Energy Gel contains branched-chain amino acids that have been shown to help prevent central fatigue by competing with tryptophan for transport across the blood brain barrier. They also contain the amino acids taurine (to help maintain heart contractility and improve cardiac output during long exercise sessions) and beta-alanine (to help promote formation of the intramuscular buffer carnosine).<\/p>"}},"59332e8e-2dda-48f9-81cd-124f9a1ce472":{"type":"question","settings":{"question":"SHOULD I USE ROCTANE ENERGY GEL DIFFERENTLY ON RACE-DAY?","answer":"<p>chase with water approximately 5 minutes before the start. It is important to practice with what you plan to use during your race, too. Your gut adapts to digest and transport dietary carbohydrate if “trained” to do so by eating carbohydrate during your training sessions. So, rule of thumb, whatever you’re using during training, plan to race with the same thing to help optimize your personal performance on race day.<\/p>"}}},"block_order":["template--16010042015906__4a1ae5e2-2a30-49d5-bff6-769272b96cd1-1668414519e48829f5-0","template--16010042015906__4a1ae5e2-2a30-49d5-bff6-769272b96cd1-1668414519e48829f5-1","template--16010042015906__4a1ae5e2-2a30-49d5-bff6-769272b96cd1-1668414519e48829f5-2","template--16010042015906__4a1ae5e2-2a30-49d5-bff6-769272b96cd1-1668414519e48829f5-3","template--16010042015906__4a1ae5e2-2a30-49d5-bff6-769272b96cd1-1668414519e48829f5-4","template--16010042015906__4a1ae5e2-2a30-49d5-bff6-769272b96cd1-1668414519e48829f5-5","template--16010042015906__4a1ae5e2-2a30-49d5-bff6-769272b96cd1-1668414519e48829f5-6","template--16010042015906__4a1ae5e2-2a30-49d5-bff6-769272b96cd1-1668414519e48829f5-7","27f762fc-c580-4269-b289-da9d334708a4","48a3ab3a-938b-447c-bbdd-54e70c1be370","2ac8f77b-14da-4c16-87af-6c69d87d2dda","21860d85-a529-4c2f-a455-7ecb43a377ae","2674c916-cbf6-44f1-a520-ac1073e338cf","1c9d6314-4a5a-43bd-ba09-45e4fd5ae6da","1dc840b5-6dc2-416d-935a-e1c0e3c755b2","f8c42ae2-3634-437d-818d-d4dd77c748fd","7cf91238-7b3b-42e5-8e35-1bdb783c4d0f","59332e8e-2dda-48f9-81cd-124f9a1ce472"],"settings":{"display_on_card":true,"heading_text_style":"body","two_columns_desktop":true,"title":"FAQ","richtext":"<p>Find the most frequently asked questions below.<\/p>","color_scheme":"tertiary","use_gradient_background":false}}},"order":["main","502b5396-367c-41d7-b6c7-a1f7892bb3c8","product-recommendations","4a1ae5e2-2a30-49d5-bff6-769272b96cd1"]}